Contact

+79260142327 (Mobile) kashirinas@rambler.ru

www.linkedin.com/in/ andreykashirin (LinkedIn) kancom.github.io (Personal)

Top Skills

Troubleshooting
MySQL
Programming

Languages

Russian

English

Andrey Kashirin

Engineering Manager, Python Team Lead Russia

Summary

I have over 15+ years of experience in engineering, of which 8 years are associated with development. In development, I managed to experience several roles: analyst, base architect, team leader, and, of course, a developer. I have also worked both in large companies with a high level of bureaucracy and startups from their foundation to commercial launch. As a result, I know and, most importantly, understand the necessary ingredients of a successful development process.

In addition, to create an effective architecture and have an upto-date set of technical skills, I am constantly engaged in active development.

I want to continue my development as an engineering expert at [python] back-end, while having significant voice at dicision making, on a relatively small team of high-level processionals, who are passionate of technology as I do

Experience

Sphere Partners
Senior Software Engineer
November 2020 - February 2021 (4 months)

Python BE

Techology stack: AWS, Azure, Spark, Hive, etc

MTS Group
Technical Manager
December 2019 - November 2020 (1 year)
Moscow, Russian Federation

Our team was involved in two parallel projects. **Both projects were succesfully led to POC presentations.**

The projects are: online subscribers geo-positioning and a troubleshooting system on the network.

HyperQuant Engineering Manager April 2019 - November 2019 (8 months)

Moscow

I manage development of several products for cryptocurrency trading. I **set up development process and launched few products in commercial.**

SysQual

3 years 6 months

Engineering Manager July 2017 - March 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

I was the first employee. I built and consequently managed engineering team (25 people). Development and delivery process.

\$1M+ sales. Product won technical part of \$10M+ tender in Tier I operator.

Python Developer October 2015 - May 2018 (2 years 8 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

Platform Engineer

Development of server side part, which controls product life-cycle at customer appliance - Element Manager System (EMS) in Network Function Virtualization (NFV) structure

Rivasense Technologies

4 years 4 months

Engineering Manager
April 2013 - July 2017 (4 years 4 months)
Moscow, Russian Federation

Achievement:

Build SW development cycle: task discussion, formalization, development, testing and implementation.

Developed architecture of complex solution from the scratch up to commercial ready system.

Form successful development team.

Intrude of continuous integration system (code fetching, verify, testing, packaging)

Intrude KPI for developer assessment.

Responsibility:

Driving product development from the company's start.

Team management (remote and local commands)

- * Team recruitment (search, interview).
- * Team assessment.
- * Team's task definitions.

Being a scrum master.

Technical support of BAs and CPO.

Writing technical requirements and documentation;

Coordination of troubleshooting of complex problems.

Management of developing and lab HW and SW infrastructure.

Tools:

Redmine

GITolite

BuildBot

Senior Database Architect

April 2013 - July 2017 (4 years 4 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

Mysql and ClickHouse

Responsibility:

Design of schema from the beginning.

Writing SQL business logic realized in DB.

Testing and choice of best performing DBMS.

DBMS, schema and query fine tuning.

DBMS:

Mysql, Percona, ClickHouse

Dimensions:

Terabytes of data and billions of rows, 24/7/265 OLTP + OLAP.

Oracle

Professional service engineer

September 2009 - July 2014 (4 years 11 months)

Level "2.5" Support Engineer

Achievements:

Implementation of several turn-key and jump in projects in several countries (including US, Brazil, UE countries).

Writing of technical and documentation for co-workers.

Development scripts for customer demands on various programming languages.

Development of engineering tools, which saves engineers' time, which were included into the product.

First launch at customer site of new E5-MS product.

Much troubleshooting efforts for customer support and project implementation, including product's code depth.

Gathering and subsequent adoption of deep network knowledge in system configuration and troubleshooting (Protocols: MAP, CAP, RANAP, BSSAP, ISUP, BICC, SIP, GTP, Dlameter, S1AP.).

Equipment:

PIC

E5-MS

Eagle5 STP

Huawei

Technical Support Engineer March 2008 - June 2009 (1 year 4 months)

Level 2 Technical Support Engineer

Achievements:

Implementation of 3 turn-key projects for Beeline@Russia (First installation of 3G of Huawei in Russia)

Preparation of standard drafts for technical documentation further used by colleagues.

Besides for "field" project, support of all Russian CDMA customers for Core Network domain.

Successful implementation of multivendor tests in Megafon lab, which required deep knowledge of protocol stack from implementer.

Responsibilities:

Engineering deployment: supervision of hardware and software installation, software installation according to quality policy, preparation engineering documentation package.

Preparation configuration for acceptance tests, preparation to integration and integration implementation.

Technical support tier II, troubleshooting and consulting.

Equipment:

MSC MSOFTX3000

MGW UMG8900

Huawei L3 switches

ZTE

After-sales technical support engneer
June 2005 - March 2008 (2 years 10 months)

Level 2 Technical Support Engineer.

Achievements:

Successful implementation of 5 full-cycle projects in Russian cities.

Regular interaction with Level 3 support Engineers during complex problem troubleshooting.

Interaction with customers during system acceptance tests and daily maintenance.

Responsibilities:

Engineering deployment: supervision of hardware installation, software installation.

System debugging, preparation to acceptance tests, preparation to integration and integration.

Technical support for customer.

Equipment:

MSC ZXG10

HLR ZXG10

Education

Mordovia State University named after N.P. Ogarev (MSU) Bachelor, of mathematics, applied mathematics and information science. (2001 - 2006)